If you collect 99 devil's keys, you can have everything in the world.
集齊99把惡魔鑰匙，你就能主宰世界
We have become wrapped up in our struggle for the keys
我們陷入了一場惡魔鑰匙爭奪戰
and finally reached the mastermind behind it all.
最後找到了幕後主使
First of all, let me tell you about Hoshin's organization.
首先我跟你介紹崩心組織的情況
"Gungnir."
“永恆之槍”
Gungnir.
永恆之槍
"Gungnir is the spear of Odin,
“永恆之槍是奧丁神的長矛
who is the god of war and death in Norse mythology."
在北歐神話中 祂是主掌戰爭和死亡的神”
Exactly what kind of organization is this?
這究竟是一個什麼樣的組織？
Strange things have been happening recently.
最近發生了很多怪事
Something is pulling the strings behind the scenes…
而在幕後操縱的就是…
Gungnir.
永恆之槍
That's not all.
不僅如此
Politicians, high-ranking policemen,
政客、警方高層
and members of the self-defense force have been mysteriously killed.
和自衛隊高官相繼離奇死亡
ACMA:GAME and Gungnir seem to be responsible.
這似乎和 ACMA:GAME和永恆之槍有關係
What's Gungnir's end game?
永恆之槍有什麼目的？
Beats me.
我也不知道
But…
不過…
They want the key owners to fight each other.
他們似乎想要鑰匙持有者互相鬥起來
Unsuspecting citizens have no idea,
雖然毫無戒備的國民渾然不知
but Gungnir's influence can be felt everywhere.
但永恆之槍的影響已四處可見
How cool is that?
很厲害吧？
I'm getting goose bumps.
我都毛骨悚然了
Show some respect.
放尊重點
Teruasa has had to live with the consequences.
你知道照朝 是以什麼心情過日子的嗎？
The baggage is still here?
累贅，你還在啊？
You're just a background character.
我都沒注意到你這個小角色
-What did you say? -Calm down.
-你說什麼？ -冷靜
You need to calm down.
是你要冷靜才對
Can you really trust this guy?
你怎麼能相信這種傢伙？
Ui. Yuki, you too.
初，還有悠季
It's too dangerous now.
接下來會很危險
You need to stay out of this.
你們不要捲進來
You need people you can rely on to help decipher the keys.
破解鑰匙需要與信任的人合作
I…
我覺得…
can't think of anyone you can trust more than Ui and Yuki.
最值得信賴的人只有他們倆
Teruasa,
照朝君
let us help you.
就讓我們幫你吧
We won't do anything that would put you in trouble.
我們絕對不會給你添麻煩的
She's right.
對
Okay. Thank you.
我知道了，謝謝
GUNGNIR
（永恆之槍）
Did you find anything on Gungnir?
找到有關永恆之槍的資訊了嗎？
Nothing.
什麼也沒找到
OROCHI searched everything.
大蛇也努力查過了
It's useless.
但是一無所獲
I see.
這樣啊
I got some interesting data
之前多虧了上杉潛夜和初
thanks to you and Senya Uesugi.
我獲得了有趣的數據
You two are like cats and dogs.
你們就像一對冤家
Thanks for the concrete example of two people who don't see eye to eye.
感謝你們提供了 兩個人針鋒相對的具體例子
Stop learning pointless stuff and get on with your work.
不要再學沒意義的東西了 繼續好好工作
Teruasa.
照朝
Sorry to barge in. I got some data on the devil's key.
抱歉不請自來 但我取得了惡魔鑰匙的資料
Everything the analytical engine found is on here.
分析機找到的數據都在裡面
Here.
給妳
Thanks, I'll check it now.
好，交給我吧
Yoo-hoo, Terurin.
小照照
-I let myself in. -Senya.
-我來了 -潛夜
-I've gotta go. -That's a great jacket.
-我先走了 -好帥氣的外套
URGENT NOTICE
（催繳通知）
WE ARE UNABLE TO CONFIRM PAYMENT
（我們無法確認付款）
AMOUNT OWED 18,000,000 YEN
（所欠金額：1800萬日元）
Yes, this is Saito from U.U. Engineering.
你好，我是UU工程公司的齊藤
Sorry to disturb you.
抱歉打擾了
My name is Inukai, from Black Size Japan.
我是黑碼日本的犬飼
I see.
你好
Yep! You seemed down in the dumps, so I got you some bread.
小照照，你看起來不開心 所以我買了麵包給你
Bread?
麵包？
Oh, right. Terurin.
對了，小照照
Know what this is? It's called a "bread clip."
知道這是什麼嗎？這叫麵包袋夾
-Heard of it? -Quiet.
-聽過這東西嗎？ -吵死了
Terurin, your lips look a bit--
小照照，你的嘴唇有點…
-Don't touch me. -They're so chapped.
-別碰我 -有點乾裂
You should use this lip balm I made.
這時候就應該擦我開發的唇膏
Look!
看
I named it Senya-kun Lip. Shall I put it on for you?
這叫“潛夜君唇膏”，要幫你擦上嗎？
-I'm good. -Pucker up.
-不用了 -嘟嘴
Get away.
不要
Dry lips are unpopular with the ladies.
嘴唇太乾的話，女生不喜歡喔
Look at this.
你們看
More numbers appear when you put three keys together,
把三把鑰匙放在一起時 會出現一些數字
and when I do a particular analysis,
經過特定分析之後
you get two numbers.
得到了兩組數字
Two numbers…
兩組數字…
Yeah.
對
If you convert it to angle and distance…
如果把數字轉化為角度和距離…
It looks like there was a devil's key here.
看來這裡有一把惡魔鑰匙
NATIONAL DIET BUILDING NATIONAL DIET PRESS CENTER
（國會議事堂，國會記者會館）
I see.
原來如此
So this is how Gungnir has been finding key owners.
永恆之槍就是這樣 找到鑰匙主人的嗎？
I guess someone from Gungnir was here, huh?
看來永恆之槍的人來過這裡
Teruasa, wait.
照朝君，等等
The coordinates are moving. The key isn't here anymore.
座標一直在移動 鑰匙已經不在那裡了
Are you Teruasa Oda?
你是織田照朝嗎？
Nice to meet you.
初次見面
I'm Nagakute, from Gungnir.
我是永恆之槍的長久手
Sorry for calling you out of the blue.
抱歉突然打給你
I'm Inukai.
我就是犬飼
You're the CEO?
你是執行長？
TAKEHIKO INUKAI
（黑碼日本，執行長犬飼武彥）
-Let me get straight to it. -Right.
-我就開門見山了 -好的
Have a seat.
請坐
This man is from Gungnir.
這是永恆之槍的人
Let's skip the pointless chitchat.
我們就不廢話了
I'm here to play you at ACMA:GAME.
我是來跟你玩ACMA:GAME的
I think that's what you want too, isn't it?
這也是你想要的，不是嗎？
Don't, Teruasa.
照朝君，別答應他
You don't know what he's after.
你還不清楚他的意圖
I've been waiting ever since that day.
從那一天起，我就一直在等待
To take revenge…
等待復仇…
Dad!
爸爸
…on the one who killed my father.
…讓殺害父親的人付出代價
I accept.
這個挑戰
Let's play.
我接受
Then…
那麼…
let the game begin.
讓遊戲開始吧
Not Gado?
不是卡多？
Gado?
卡多？
Don't tell me you'd prefer that tacky brute of a cow?
莫非你覺得那頭沒品味的凶殘蠻牛 比我還要好？
Not at all!
不是的
It's just that Gado's the only devil Terurin has met so far.
小照照那麼說 是因為他只見過卡多這個惡魔
How pitiful, to have only met Gado.
只知道卡多這個惡魔，真可悲
I'm the game master, Korjia.
我是遊戲管理員，可魯佳
I take fairness very seriously.
我會秉持公正嚴明的態度
I promise to be a dignified judge.
保證做出莊重的評判
There are different types of devil?
沒想到還有不同種類的惡魔
Korjia's personality is totally different. I wonder if it will affect the game…
可魯佳的性格完全不一樣 這會對遊戲有影響嗎？
The players are
遊戲玩家是
Yoichi Nagakute and Teruasa Oda, correct?
長久手洋一和織田照朝，對嗎？
Yes.
對
Although I don't mind if all three of you come at me at once.
我不介意你們三個一起上
Yoichi Nagakute, state your demands.
長久手洋一，說出你的要求
I want Teruasa to swear never to defy Gungnir,
我要他發誓 從今以後不跟永恆之槍作對
and offer total obedience from here on out.
並且對永恆之槍絕對服從
Total obedience?
絕對服從？
Nice one!
不錯喔
Teruasa Oda, what are your demands?
織田照朝，你有什麼要求？
He will tell me everything he knows about Gungnir.
我要他說出 他對永恆之槍掌握的所有情報
One player risks total obedience to Gungnir.
一個玩家要求對永恆之槍絕對服從
The other risks all of Gungnir's information.
另一個玩家要永恆之槍的所有情報
The purity of your desires is admirable.
這麼純粹的欲望很不錯
Take your oaths.
那就宣誓吧
I will fight for my desires.
我會為我的欲望而戰
I will triumph for my desires.
我會為我的欲望奪勝
-I swear on the devil.
-我向惡魔宣誓
Here is the game!
這就是這次的遊戲
"Hundred Contest."
“百金爭奪”
I can't believe the company that made OROCHI
第4集
is suffering from financial difficulty.
竟然會資金周轉困難，真是想不到
We're extremely willing to work with you.
我們願意全力與你們合作
That's amazing.
真的嗎？
Thank you!
那太感謝了
I just have one condition.
不過我有一個條件
I want to take over OROCHI's rights.
我要獲得大蛇的所有權
If you agree to this condition,
如果你同意這個條件
I'll make sure your company thrives.
我保證貴公司一定能撐下去
O.B. I can't spot any abnormalities.
OB，沒有任何異樣
Wow, what a cutie.
真可愛啊
Can you stop messing about?
你能不能別搗亂？
Quit nagging.
別嘮叨啦
Wish I was allowed to play.
我也好想玩這個遊戲
Put it back.
快放回去
I'm really sorry.
不好意思
It'll be hard to tell them apart with the body totally smashed.
身體碎成這樣 就難以區分是什麼棋子了
I'll make a new one.
我再準備一個新的吧
Lucky for you, Kor-chin is very forgiving.
真不愧是可魯佳，果然寬宏大量
Gado and I are totally different.
我和卡多可不一樣
You really hate him, huh?
妳是有多討厭卡多啊？
I'll explain the rules.
現在我來解釋遊戲規則
For each player,
兩名玩家
it's a fight for 100 gold coins.
要爭奪一百枚金幣
The number of coins to be wagered is decided at the start of each round.
要爭奪的金幣數量 在每一回合開始時決定
In this case, you would play for 30 coins.
以這個情況來說 你們要爭奪30枚金幣
The importance of each round hangs on the number of coins at stake.
當然，每一回合的重要性 會根據金幣的數量而定
Next, the players choose which piece to use.
接著玩家將選擇使用哪個棋子
In strength order, there's a king,
棋子按強弱排序，有國王
general,
將軍
knight,
騎士
soldier,
士兵
and lastly, a commoner.
最後則是平民
But the king can be defeated by the commoner.
但是最強的國王 有可能被最弱的平民打敗
Once a piece has been used, it cannot be used again.
使用過的棋子不能再次使用
The player must choose his piece and place it in the opening.
玩家將選好的棋子放進空格裡
Once both have chosen, the choices are revealed.
雙方選擇完畢之後 棋子就會顯示出來
Now for the last twist.
還有最後的反轉
When you use a level-up diamond,
如果你們使用這顆升級鑽石
the piece you have chosen levels up to the next rank.
你們選擇的棋子將升一級
However, like the pieces, diamonds can only be used once.
但是它和棋子一樣，只能用一次
Then the winner is decided.
最後，勝負就會揭曉了
The gold coins are awarded to the winner.
贏的人將獲得金幣
So even if you're about to lose,
也就是說，如果你出的棋子等級較低
you can use the diamond,
在棋子只差一級時，可以使用鑽石
and make it a tie.
這樣就可以打成平局了
What happens to the gold if it's a tie?
在平局的情況下，金幣怎麼分？
It is discarded.
金幣將會作廢
Neither of you get the coins.
誰都得不到金幣
What if both players have the same number of coins after five rounds?
如果在五回合之後 兩個玩家金幣數量一樣，那怎麼算？
The player who still has a diamond wins.
還剩有鑽石的玩家獲勝
If both players have used their diamonds, the game starts over.
如果雙方都使用了鑽石 那麼遊戲就會重新開始
What if you use the diamond on a king?
如果在出國王時使用鑽石會怎麼樣？
It becomes a level two king.
棋子會成為二級國王
In that case, you must use a diamond on the commoner
在這種情況下 你必須對平民使用鑽石
to beat the level two king.
才能打敗二級國王
Any other questions?
還有問題嗎？
So, a fight to the bitter end.
那就盡情戰鬥吧
Let the game Hundred Contest begin!
“百金爭奪”開始
ROUND ONE TERUASA ODA - YOICHI NAGAKUTE
（第一回合）
100 COINS REMAINING
（剩餘100枚）
You will play for seven coins in round one.
第一回合要爭奪的金幣是七枚
Choose your piece, and place it in the opening.
選擇你們要出的棋子 然後放到空格裡
It makes sense to use the stronger piece
在這個遊戲裡 在金幣多的回合裡使用強大的棋子
when there are more coins at stake.
這是合理的玩法
There are only seven coins this time.
這一回合只有七枚金幣
So…
所以…
The best strategy is to save the commoners to beat the king,
把平民留著用來打國王
and use the soldiers instead, right?
然後出士兵，這才是最佳策略
So you'd think.
你是這麼想的吧？
You've played three games so far.
你玩了三次惡魔遊戲
You won against small fry Maruko and Hyodo,
雖然贏了丸子和兵頭這兩個小嘍囉
but lost miserably to Senya Uesugi.
但是卻慘敗給上杉潛夜
You're desperate to win this game.
你一定很想贏這場比賽
But the more you focus on winning,
但是你越想贏
the more clearly I will know
我就越知道
exactly which piece you're going to choose.
你打算出哪個棋子
I already know something about you.
我也知道了你的一些背景
You…
長久手先生
have experience working in medicine, don't you?
你當過醫療工作者，對吧？
O.B. I can't spot any abnormalities.
OB ，沒有任何異樣
O.B. is a medical term meaning, "No pathological findings."
OB是醫療用語，意思是“沒有異常”
Why would someone who wanted to preserve life
一個救死扶傷的人
join an organization like Gungnir?
為什麼會加入永恆之槍這種組織？
Aren't you going to answer?
你不打算回答嗎？
Just like you said.
你說得對
There was a time
我曾經
when I worked in a hospital specializing in intensive care.
在一家醫院負責照顧重症病患
The reason I worked there
我之所以在那裡工作
was because I wanted to help bring my wife out of a coma.
是為了治好昏迷的妻子
But no amount of treatment could bring her back to consciousness.
但是不論採取什麼治療 我妻子就是醒不過來
I was in the depths of despair.
這將我逼到了絕望的邊緣
Then one day,
然後有一天
I witnessed a miracle.
奇蹟發生了
Someone visited the hospital and cured my wife completely.
有一個人來到醫院治癒了我妻子
That person was the leader of Gungnir.
這個人就是永恆之槍的領袖
The Guide.
引領者大人
Guide?
引領者？
The Guide has power beyond human comprehension.
引領者大人擁有超越人類智慧的力量
An ordinary person like you cannot understand it.
像你這樣的凡人是理解不了的
If you stand in his way,
如果你擋他的路
I will destroy you.
我就會除掉你
Yowza.
好厲害啊
Just watching this making my heart race.
光是在一旁看著就讓我熱血沸騰了
I'm so turned on.
我都硬起來了
Yuki.
悠季
I need to concentrate.
我需要集中精神
Can you shut him up for me?
麻煩叫潛夜閉嘴
Okay.
好的
How many times do I have to tell you?
我跟你說多少次了？
Stop messing about.
不要搗亂了
I'm not doing anything wrong.
我又沒做什麼
All you do is nag, nag, nag.
倒是妳，也太嘮叨了吧
It is time.
好了，時間到
I've chosen.
我選好了
Me too.
我也選好了
Now I will reveal both pieces.
那我來公開雙方的棋子
Both of you played a soldier.
你們都出了士兵
If you wish to use a diamond, place it in the hole.
如果你們要使用鑽石 就把它放進圓孔裡
We both took the expected approach.
我們都用了合乎常規的打法
The real game starts now.
接下來才是重頭戲
Now…
接下來…
How's he gonna play it?
他會怎麼玩？
Time to find out who the winner is.
現在判定勝負
The strength of both pieces is evenly matched.
雙方棋子的強弱等級一樣
The first round is a draw.
因此第一回合是平局
Seven coins discarded.
七枚金幣作廢
Nagakute didn't use the diamond either.
長久手也沒使用鑽石
He must think the same.
他也知道
The point of the game is when to use the diamond.
勝負的關鍵是在什麼時候使用鑽石
ROUND TWO
（第二回合）
93 COINS REMAINING
（剩餘93枚）
The first round was a tie,
第一回合打成了平局
so 93 coins remain.
因此還剩93枚金幣
The second round is for 42 coins.
第二回合是42枚金幣
Forty-two?
42枚？
To gain the majority, I need 47 coins.
93枚的一半是47枚
If I win, I only need five coins in the final three rounds.
如果我能贏下第二回合 在最後三回合中，我只需要再贏五枚
In other words, this round is a crucial turning point.
也就是說，第二回合是重要的轉捩點
Choose your piece and place it in the opening.
請玩家選擇棋子，然後放到空格裡
I need to win this round no matter what.
不論如何，我都要贏下這一回合
So I should use the strongest piece, the king.
所以我應該使用最強的棋子，國王
KING
（國王）
But if he does the same, it'd be better to play the commoner.
但是如果他也這樣出棋子 我最好出平民
COMMONER
（平民）
Or if he plays the commoner, I need to play the general.
或者如果他出平民，我應該出將軍
GENERAL
（將軍）
Either way, there are three choices, but definitely not the knight.
反正是在騎士以外的三個中出一個
But between these three, it's pretty much rock-paper-scissors.
但是出這三個棋子就像猜拳一樣
A one in three chance of winning. A one in three chance of losing.
輸贏的機率分別都是三分之一
A one in three chance of a tie.
平局的機率也是三分之一
Even if I lose the second round,
如果我在第二回合輸了
the way I lose will change things going forward.
不同的輸法將會改變之後的戰局
If I lose with the king,
如果我出國王輸了
in the third round, I can only draw to Nagakute's general.
在第三回合裡 我只有出將軍才有可能打成平局
If I lose with the commoner, then the best I can hope for is a tie.
如果我出平民輸了 最好的情況也是平局
But if I lose with the general,
但如果我出將軍輸了
depending on the number of coins, and whether I can keep the king,
根據之後金幣的數量 以及我是否還留有國王
I could just about make it.
我還有些微的獲勝機會
So basically, I shouldn't play the king or commoner,
也就是說，我不該出國王或平民
but go for the least risky option, the general.
而是該出風險最低的將軍
So I should try to tie, by using the general,
所以這一回合我應該出將軍 力爭打成平局
and then win the game in the following rounds.
然後在下一回合贏得遊戲
You're considering the risk of losing, right?
你正在考慮失敗的風險，對吧？
Just like I told you,
我跟你說過
I know everything you're thinking.
你在想什麼我全都知道
That's why I have a proposal.
我有一個提議
Shall we draw in the second round too?
和第一回合一樣 我們在第二回合打成平局如何？
Draw on purpose?
故意打成平局？
We won't get anywhere trying to read each other's minds.
我們這樣相互試探也探不出什麼結果
Even so, I don't want to lose one third of the coins.
而且我也不願意 在一個回合裡輸掉三分之一的金幣
So why don't we both play our knights and draw,
所以我們何不都出騎士 在這一回合打成平局
and then decide the game on the third round?
然後在第三回合決出勝負？
Taking your time to enjoy the process
慢慢享受遊戲的樂趣
is the best part of ACMA:GAME.
才是ACMA:GAME的絕妙之處
I don't need your opinion.
這個不用你教我
If I agree and play my knight,
如果我同意你的提議，出了騎士
how do I know you won't play the general or king?
你怎麼保證不會出將軍或國王？
If you agree to my proposal,
如果你同意我的提議
I'll show you my piece before I place it down.
我會在第二回合先給你看棋再出棋子
Of course,
當然
I expect you to do the same in return.
我希望你也能這麼做
Now you're talking.
這才像話
So, what will it be?
那麼，你會怎麼出呢？
Things are heating up.
這下可有趣了
What's this guy's devil power?
這傢伙擁有什麼惡魔之力？
Surely whatever I do, he'll win somehow.
不論我怎麼出 他都會想盡辦法贏過我
But I don't know what he is capable of,
但我不知道他的能力是什麼
so I shouldn't do anything stupid.
所以不能貿然行動
Get the show on the road.
快點玩吧
The suspense is killing me.
拖拖拉拉的，煩死人了
I'm falling asleep here.
我都快睡著了
Cut the crap.
別搗亂了
Teruasa is fighting a serious battle.
照朝君正在認真地戰鬥
Who are you again?
我忘了，妳是哪位？
Yuki Manabe.
真鍋悠季
You've got a nice slap on you.
妳這一巴掌打得真好
I like it.
我喜歡
I'm gonna call you Yukky.
從現在開始，我就叫妳小悠季
-Hey-- -Such a pleasure, Yukky.
-喂 -請多關照，小悠季
Get off me.
你快放手
Sorry!
不好意思
I feel bad for you.
我真同情你
Your friends are really dragging you down.
有這種扯後腿的朋友
Forty-two coins is huge win.
能贏得42枚金幣非同小可
The one thing I have to avoid is losing this round.
這一回合我絕對不能輸
Nagakute's goal is to get me to play the knight,
長久手的目標是要我出騎士
and then beat me with a king or general.
然後用國王或將軍打敗我
If he can win with either, there's no reason to use the king.
如果他用哪個都能打敗我 那麼現在沒有理由浪費掉國王
So he'll use the general.
所以這一回合他會出將軍
I accept your proposal.
我接受你的提議
Then…
那麼…
we'll put them down on three.
數到三，同時放進去吧
Three,
三
two,
二
one.
一
I have checked the pieces.
已確認棋子放置完畢
I will reveal what each player set down.
現在我將公開雙方的棋子
A knight?
騎士？
You didn't expect me to follow through on my promise?
你沒想到我會按照提議出騎士？
Is he using a devil power?
莫非他使用了惡魔之力？
You're busy thinking,
你現在正在想
"Is that really a knight?"
“這真的是騎士嗎？”
And now you hesitate.
你現在猶豫了
If you lose,
如果你輸了這一回合
you'll lose a grand total of 42 coins.
就會輸掉42枚金幣
If you wish to use a diamond, place it in the hole.
如果想要使用鑽石 就把它放到圓孔裡
What should I do?
我該怎麼做？
He used a diamond.
照朝君使用鑽石了
And now for the results.
現在判定勝負
Based on the strength of the pieces,
由於兩個棋子強弱等級相同
round two is a tie.
第二回合打成平局
Forty-two coins are void.
42枚金幣作廢
A tie?
平局？
So it wasn't just Teruasa, but both of you used a diamond?
所以不只有照朝君用了鑽石 你們兩個都用了？
It's his devil power.
這就是他的惡魔之力
That's right.
說得對
My devil power
我的惡魔之力
is called Poor Scapegoat.
叫做“拙劣的代罪羔羊”
Also known as a shoddy substitution.
也叫“拙劣的替換”
I can change…
我能改變…
the appearance of an object.
物體的外觀
Like the name implies, it's a pretty shitty skill.
名字取得真好，這能力是滿拙劣的
I don't deny it.
我不否認
But the one you should be laughing at is Teruasa,
但你要嘲笑的人是他
who was tricked into using a diamond.
他被我騙了，以致於使用了鑽石
Wait,
等等
But Teruasa has stronger pieces left.
照朝君剩下的棋子更強
He can still win.
他還有勝算
You're wrong.
不
Teruasa already knows.
他心知肚明
His chances of winning are very slim.
他獲勝的可能性極低
How?
怎麼會這樣？
-The diamond. -What?
-關鍵在鑽石 -什麼？
He can use his diamond to make a level two king.
他可以用鑽石把國王變成二級國王
But Terurin has used his diamond,
而小照照已經用了鑽石
so he can't level up his commoner.
所以他不能將他的平民升級了
It's a guaranteed win for Nagakute.
長久手肯定還能再贏一回合
If he takes that win on a round with a high number of coins,
如果他在金幣數量多的那一回合贏了
it's the end.
遊戲就結束了
Did that sink in?
你現在明白了嗎？
I have an impossible advantage.
我佔有絕對優勢
Time for the third round.
那麼，現在開始第三回合
ROUND THREE
（第三回合）
Since the second round was a tie,
由於第二回合打成了平局
there are 51 gold coins left.
所以剩餘的金幣是51枚
Three rounds to go.
還剩下三個回合
It could be three lots of 17, or something like that.
金幣的分配可以是每回合17枚 或類似的數量
Then he still stands a chance.
這樣機會雖小，但還是有勝算的
But if the number is 26 or more…
但如果有一回合的金幣數量 是半數26枚以上的話…
Thirty gold coins are up for grabs in round three.
第三回合要爭奪的金幣是30枚
At the end of this round,
在第三回合結束後
there will be 21 gold coins remaining.
剩餘的金幣數量是21枚
Whatever happens cannot be reversed.
到時候，局勢將無法逆轉
Victory will be decided.
因此這一回合將會決出勝者
It's over.
結束了
Teruasa Oda.
織田照朝
I must admit,
我有言在先
I am not as forgiving as you and Senya Uesugi.
我可不像你和上杉潛夜那樣仁慈
You will serve as Gungnir's slave…
你到死為止
until the day you die.
都要當永恆之槍的奴隸
Teruasa…
照朝君…
Choose your piece and place it in the opening.
選擇你們的棋子，然後放到空格裡
He's already used his diamond.
他已經用了鑽石
If I choose the king
我如果出國王
and use my diamond, victory is certain.
然後再使用鑽石，就必勝無疑了
I will reveal both pieces.
現在公開雙方的棋子
A commoner?
平民？
That doesn't make sense.
這不合理
If you wish to use a diamond, place it in the hole.
如果想要使用鑽石 就把它放到圓孔裡
I've won.
我贏了
My Guide,
引領者大人
I dedicate this victory
我要將這場勝利
to you.
獻給您
Yoichi Nagakute.
長久手洋一
Checkmate.
你被將了一軍
Victory is decided.
現在判定勝負
The pieces are a level two king,
雙方的棋子是二級國王
and a level two commoner.
和二級平民
The commoner wins the gold coins.
出平民的玩家獲得金幣
Therefore, Teruasa Oda is the winner.
所以勝者是織田照朝
You did it!
太好了，照朝君
Nonsense.
不可能
There must be a mistake!
一定是弄錯了
You used a diamond in the second round.
你在第二回合已經用了鑽石
I didn't use it then.
那時候我沒用鑽石
When I was listening to the rules of the game,
在聽“百金爭奪”遊戲的規則時
I realized that the whole game hung on a diamond.
我意識到勝負的關鍵在於鑽石
So…
所以…
I need to concentrate.
我需要集中精神
Can you shut him up for me?
麻煩叫潛夜閉嘴
Okay.
好的
In the first round, I put a Mog chocolate wrapper in the hole,
在第一回合裡 我把莫格巧克力包裝紙放進了圓孔裡
to check that Korjia wouldn't challenge my method.
從而確認了可魯佳對此沒有意見
In the second round, I used the cap of the lip balm I got from Senya.
然後在第二回合裡 我用了從潛夜那裡拿來的唇膏蓋
To make you think I had used the diamond.
讓你誤以為我使用了鑽石
That's a lie.
你撒謊
If you did, then in the second round,
如果是這樣，在第二回合裡
my general would have beaten your knight!
我的將軍應該能打敗你的騎士才對
Just like you,
我和你做的一樣
my knight was really a general.
我的騎士其實是將軍
But in my case,
只不過
I used brute force.
我用的是蠻力
I was in front of you the whole time!
我全程都在你面前
There's no way I would have missed something so obvious.
這麼明顯的動作，我不可能沒看到
That's why…
所以…
I let you have it your way.
我按你的話去做了
Although I don't mind if all three of you come at me at once.
我不介意你們三個一起上
I need to concentrate on the game.
我需要集中精神
GIVE THIS PIECE TO SENYA
（把棋子給潛夜）
Can you shut him up for me?
麻煩叫潛夜閉嘴
Okay.
好的
How many times do I have to tell you?
我跟你說多少次了？
Stop messing about.
不要搗亂了
What's wrong?
我又沒做什麼
All you do is nag, nag, nag.
倒是妳，也太嘮叨了吧
I trusted Senya to understand what I wanted him to do.
我相信潛夜會明白我的意圖
You've got a nice slap on you.
妳這一巴掌打得真好
I like it.
我喜歡
I'm gonna call you Yukky.
從現在開始，我就叫妳小悠季
-Hey-- -Such a pleasure, Yukky.
-喂 -請多關照，小悠季
-Get off me. -And so,
-你快放手 -就這樣
he gave the two altered pieces…
他把兩個改動過的棋子…
-Sorry! -…back to Yuki.
-不好意思 -…交還給了悠季
Just like you wanted, right?
這就是你要的吧，小照照？
But I gotta say, I didn't expect a slap.
不過，沒想到我會挨一巴掌
Right, sorry!
不好意思
Although, you were winding me up pretty bad.
不過，誰叫你一直激怒我
Who the hell does he think he is?
他以為他是誰？
That was a risky gamble.
這是一場利害攸關的賭博
Messing with something prepared by the devil…
你竟然弄壞了惡魔準備的棋子…
They could have ended up unrecognizable.
這樣可能無法辨別是哪個棋子
I don't think so.
不會的
When that happened before…
之前可魯佳說
It'll be hard to tell them apart with the body totally smashed.
身體碎成這樣 就難以區分是什麼棋子了
I'll make a new one.
我再準備一個新的吧
These pieces…
這些棋子…
look identical except from the crown.
除了頭冠以外，看起來都一樣
Most people would identify the piece by the crown.
大多數人通常會透過頭冠來辨別棋子
But,
但是
Korjia specifically mentioned the body.
可魯佳特別提到了身體
That's when I thought.
那時候我就想
Korjia didn't tell them apart by the crown,
可魯佳不是靠頭冠來辨別它們
but by something inside its body.
而是靠它們身體裡的某個東西
If so,
所以
it wouldn't make a difference if I switched the crowns.
即使我更換了頭冠 它們的身分也不會改變
Nagakute,
長久手先生
you lose.
你輸了
A fascinating battle.
真是一場有趣的對決
The game Hundred Contest is complete.
“百金爭奪”到此結束
Will you share everything you know about Gungnir?
你能告訴我 你對永恆之槍掌握的所有情報嗎？
What's happened?
怎麼回事？
A debt to be paid.
欠的債總是要還的
Who are you?
你們是誰？
What do you mean?
你這話是什麼意思？
This place…
這裡是…
Seems his memory was tampered with
他在ACMA:GAME中敗北後
by his defeat in ACMA:GAME.
記憶似乎被人篡改了
That's not all.
不僅如此
If he loses again,
他被精心訓練過
he has been carefully conditioned to lose his memory completely.
如果再輸掉遊戲，他將會完全失憶
So what about the info on Gungnir?
那永恆之槍的情報呢？
Don't ask me.
他什麼都不知道
Guess we're back to square one.
我們又毫無進展了
Wait.
等等
My wife.
我妻子
My wife, where is she?
我妻子，她在哪裡？
My wife had six months to live.
我妻子只剩下六個月能活
I have to watch her.
我必須陪在她身邊
If I'm not by her side, she'll die.
如果我不在她身邊，她會死的
My wife…
我妻子…
I…
我…
Why am I alive?
我到底活著還有什麼意義？
I see.
我知道了
I got confirmation.
我確認過了
CHAIRMAN ODA INCIDENT
（織田會長事件）
Yoichi Nagakute's wife died seven years ago.
長久手洋一的妻子在七年前就去世了
How awful.
真遺憾
How is Nagakute?
現在長久手先生怎麼樣？
His mental health deteriorated suddenly,
他的精神狀況突然惡化
and a hospital I know took him in.
他住進了我認識的一家醫院
Recently,
最近
I've been thinking a lot about what my dad said.
我經常想起父親說過的話
The flames of desire ignite conflict.
欲望的火焰會點燃衝突
Try to become someone who can save those
你試著成為一個拯救者吧
who become consumed by desire.
拯救被欲望吞噬的人
Those who are taken by desire,
那些為欲望所困的人
and consumed by it,
那些被欲望吞噬的人
are those in misery.
都是很悲慘的人
If I'm going to save those people,
我如果要拯救這些人
I need to fight Gungnir.
就要跟永恆之槍鬥爭到底
Thank you.
謝謝
Yuki.
悠季
Can I speak to you?
我們能談談嗎？
I…
我…
Well…
那個…
Remind me, how long have we been working together?
我們在一起工作多久了？
What's wrong with you?
你怎麼了，初？
You sound like an old man.
你怎麼像上了年紀的上司一樣講話？
I've always been grateful to you.
我一直很感謝妳
I don't even pay you that much.
是這樣的，我付的薪水也不高
I'm sure you could work somewhere with better conditions.
我覺得妳可以去條件更好的公司工作
Can I tell you what your problem is?
我可以告訴你，你的問題在哪裡嗎？
You jump to conclusions by spending too much time thinking alone.
你總是一個人想太多 然後自己下結論
Isn't it exhausting?
這樣不會很累嗎？
Contrary to what you might think,
我這個人比你想的
I've always been simple and self-centered.
要更簡單、更以自己為中心
I like it here.
我喜歡這裡
That's why I work here.
所以我才在這裡工作
If I get to keep working with you and OROCHI,
以後也一樣 能和初君以及大蛇一起工作
then I'll be okay.
那樣就夠了
Especially if Teruasa comes over from time to time.
如果照朝君偶爾也可以過來玩 那就更好了
Don't invite Senya Uesugi though.
但是上杉潛夜就算了吧
I see.
我知道了
I'm sorry,
抱歉
I'm afraid that
你的條件
I have to refuse your offer.
我恐怕必須拒絕
My colleagues and I will work hard
為了讓公司活下去
to ensure our company's survival alone.
我和夥伴們會一起努力的
I understand. But take a look at this.
我知道了，不過你看看這個
SECURITIES DISHONOR NOTICE
（證券退票通知）
When investors and banks see this notice,
看到這份退票通知後
they won't want to invest in U.U. Engineering.
投資人和銀行 是不會給UU工程公司資金的
If that happens, you'll go bankrupt.
這樣一來，你的公司就倒閉了
AI OROCHI will be seized by Mitsuba bank,
人工智慧大蛇將會被三葉銀行扣押
and I will buy it out, as arranged.
到時候我再下手買過來就好了
You tricked me?
你耍了我？
Your developer is amazing and so is OROCHI.
大蛇和它的開發者確實很優秀
However,
但是
you are out of your depth.
你的能力就差了點
They'd be better off without you in the picture.
離開了你，他們才能發展得更好
Yoo-hoo, Terurin!
嗨，小照照
Yukarin's going to be in a drama.
小紫要演電視劇了
She got lucky with the devil's key.
惡魔鑰匙帶給她好運了
You seem pleased.
你看起來很高興
I like girls who are honest about what they want.
我喜歡誠實面對欲望的女生
What do you want?
你有什麼事？
You didn't come here for small talk.
你不會為了閒聊才來這裡的
I want your opinion.
我想聽聽小照照的意見
My opinion?
意見？
You got it.
你收到郵件了
INVITATION - TERUASA ODA
（邀請函，織田照朝）
YOU ARE INVITED TO AN ACMA:GAME TOURNAMENT
（我們邀請您 參加ACMA:GAME錦標賽）
IF YOU WIN YOU WILL RECEIVE A DEVIL'S KEY
（如果贏了比賽 您將獲得惡魔鑰匙）
WOULD YOU LIKE TO ATTEND?
（您想要參加嗎？是，否）
Well, what you gonna do?
你有什麼打算，小照照？
This is a trap set by Gungnir.
這是永恆之槍設的圈套
It's too dangerous.
會非常危險
Don't say things you don't mean.
不要說違心的話
I had already made up my mind.
我已經決定好了
Whatever danger awaits,
無論前方有什麼危險
I will crush Gungnir's ambitions.
我都會摧毀永恆之槍的企圖
Hey, wait.
站住
Compared to Teruasa,
和照朝相比
I'm…
我…
Drink this.
請喝下這個
NEXT EPISODE
（下集預告）
The ultimate ACMA:GAME begins.
終極ACMA:GAME開始了
I already have you in my trap.
你中了我的圈套
The ability of the real devil.
真正的惡魔的能力
BEST FRIENDS BECOME WORST ENEMIES
（知己成為勁敵）
Why?
為什麼？
I've always wanted to fight you.
我早就想跟你一決高下了